<bill session="112" type="s" number="1793" updated="2012-12-19T12:09:21-05:00">
	<state datetime="2012-12-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="2012-12-17" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-11-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Investigative Assistance for Violent Crimes Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Investigative Assistance for Violent Crimes Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Investigative Assistance for Violent Crimes Act of 2012</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify the statutory authority for the longstanding practice of the Department of Justice of providing investigatory assistance on request of State and local authorities with respect to certain serious violent crimes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412247"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-11-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-11-17"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on the Judiciary"/><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-11-17"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="233" datetime="2011-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 233.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2012-12-17"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8087"/></action>
		<vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2012-12-17" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S8087"/></vote>
		<action datetime="2012-12-18T10:01:00-05:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2012-12-18"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2012-12-18T17:40:00-05:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="2076" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="2076" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Violent crime"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s3341"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/17/2011--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Investigative Assistance for Violent Crimes Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Attorney General (AG) and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), at the request of an appropriate law enforcement official of a state or political subdivision, to assist in the investigation of violent acts and shootings occurring in venues such as schools, colleges, universities, nonfederal office buildings, malls, and other public places, and in the investigation of mass killings and attempted mass killings. Defines &quot;mass killings&quot; as three or more killings in a single incident. Authorizes the AG to pay rewards up to $3 million (currently, $2 million), subject to exceptions, pursuant to public advertisements for assistance to the Department of Justice (DOJ). Allows funds available to the AG for the FBI for detection, investigation, and prosecution of crimes against the United States to be used to deploy tactical response, command and control, and other crisis-management assets of the FBI, as appropriate. Requires any such conduct or assistance to be presumptively within the scope of federal office or employment.

	</summary>
</bill>
