<bill session="112" type="s" number="3304" updated="2012-11-24T17:41:04-05:00">
	<state datetime="2012-06-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2012-06-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2012-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Buildings Designation Act of 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Buildings Designation Act of 2012</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to redesignate the Environmental Protection Agency Headquarters located at 1200 Pennsylvania Avenue N.W. in Washington, D.C., as the &quot;William Jefferson Clinton Federal Building&quot;, to redesignate the Federal building and United States Courthouse located at 200 East Wall Street in Midland, Texas, as the &quot;George H.W. Bush and George W. Bush United States Courthouse and George Mahon Federal Building&quot;, and to designate the Federal building housing the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives Headquarters located at 99 New York Avenue N.E., Washington D.C., as the &quot;Eliot Ness ATF Building&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2012-06-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2012-06-21"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2012-07-10"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="443" datetime="2012-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 443.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="362" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
		<term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
		<term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Federal Buildings Designation Act of 2012 - Redesignates: (1) the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) headquarters located at 1200 Pennsylvania Avenue N.W., Washington, DC, known as the Ariel Rios Building, as the &quot;William Jefferson Clinton Federal Building&quot;; and (2) the federal building and U.S.courthouse located at 200 East Wall Street in Midland, Texas, known as the George Mahon Federal Building, as the &quot;George H.W. Bush and George W. Bush United States Courthouse and George Mahon Federal Building.&quot; Designates: (1) the federal building housing the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) headquarters located at 99 New York Avenue N.E., Washington, DC, as the &quot;Eliot Ness ATF Building&quot;; and (2) the reflecting pool located on the grounds of such building as the &quot;Ariel Rios Reflecting Pool.&quot;

	</summary>
</bill>
